<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>change data capture on Alex Mitelman</title>
    <link>https://mitelman.engineering/tags/change-data-capture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in change data capture on Alex Mitelman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mitelman.engineering/tags/change-data-capture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>System Design Weekly 016: July 2021</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/016/</guid>
      <description>Highlights DoorDash: Building Faster Indexing with Apache Kafka and Elasticsearch The DoorDash team faced an issue of a very long time for updating the search index. They&amp;rsquo;ve built a search system relying on open source technologies. It uses Kafka as a message queue and for data storage, Flink for data transformation, and sending data to Elasticsearch. A reliable indexing system would ensure that changes in stores and items are reflected in the search index in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Design Weekly 008: May 2021</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/008/</guid>
      <description>Highlights DoorDash: Optimizing OpenTelemetry’s Span Processor for High Throughput and Low CPU Costs With an effort to migrate from the monolith to microservices, there is a need to trace requests between these services. OpenTelemetry is a new project aiming to become a standard. As a request hits a system, OpenTelemetry assigns a unique ID, all the underlying services (called spans) receive the same ID. Spans data is being collected on a local collector, then it&amp;rsquo;s sent to a collector gateway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Design Weekly 005: April 2021</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/005/</guid>
      <description>Highlights Kiwi.com: Nonstop Operations with Scylla Even Through the OVHcloud Fire Fire on French OVHcloud affected four datacenters: SBG2 was destroyed, SBG1 adjacent rooms were partially on fire, SBG3 and SBG4 were switched off to fight the fire. Overall, 3.6 million websites were affected, including banks and mail servers.
Kiwi.com uses Scylla - NoSQL database, as a highly available and resilient solution. Their monitoring system detected spikes as nodes went down but later other OVHcloud datacenters took over the requests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
