<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>elasticsearch on Alex Mitelman</title>
    <link>https://mitelman.engineering/tags/elasticsearch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in elasticsearch on Alex Mitelman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mitelman.engineering/tags/elasticsearch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>System Design Weekly 016: July 2021</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/016/</guid>
      <description>Highlights DoorDash: Building Faster Indexing with Apache Kafka and Elasticsearch The DoorDash team faced an issue of a very long time for updating the search index. They&amp;rsquo;ve built a search system relying on open source technologies. It uses Kafka as a message queue and for data storage, Flink for data transformation, and sending data to Elasticsearch. A reliable indexing system would ensure that changes in stores and items are reflected in the search index in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Design Weekly 004: March 2021</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/system-design-weekly/004/</guid>
      <description>Highlights Aurora: Payment Acquiring Solution with CockroachDB on Kubernetes Aurora is the company that handles credit card payments. Such transactions should work all the time, be consistent and scalable. That&amp;rsquo;s why they migrate from PostgreSQL to CockroachDB: eventual consistency is not an option in this business. CockroachDB guarantees serializable transactions. This blog post describes higher level architecture of the solution. Tech stack: .NET Core C#, ReactJS, CockroachDB.
Key takeaways. Hybryd-Cloud: Google Cloud + 2 co-location, never be 100% cloud or 100% private, hence no vendor lock, better availability if certain cloud provider goes down.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
