<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Alex Mitelman</title>
    <link>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Alex Mitelman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mitelman.engineering/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amazon API Gateway with Lambda is a next generation of web frameworks</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/python-best-practice/amazon-api-gateway-with-lambda-is-a-next-generation-of-web-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/python-best-practice/amazon-api-gateway-with-lambda-is-a-next-generation-of-web-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>A short history of web frameworks What is a web framework? A web framework is a set of tools for the rapid development of server-side applications that provides a boilerplate to simplify the implementation of common tasks. According to MDN, those tasks are routing URLs to appropriate handlers, interacting with databases, supporting sessions and user authorization, formatting output (e.g. HTML, JSON, XML), and improving security against web attacks. The most popular web frameworks are Ruby on Rails, Django, Flask, FastAPI, Express, Laravel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Best Practices for a New Project in 2021</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/automating-python-best-practices-for-a-new-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/automating-python-best-practices-for-a-new-project/</guid>
      <description>Intro The goal of this tutorial is to describe Python development ecosystem. It can be helpful for someone coming to Python from another programming language.
They say that you should stick to algorithms and data structures, that you can learn a new language in just a couple of weeks, that it&amp;rsquo;s just a new syntax. I completely agree that algorithms and data structures are extremely important but when it comes to language it&amp;rsquo;s slightly more than just syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
