<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>api gateway on Alex Mitelman</title>
    <link>https://mitelman.engineering/tags/api-gateway/</link>
    <description>Recent content in api gateway on Alex Mitelman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mitelman.engineering/tags/api-gateway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Follow up on Serverless Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/follow-up-on-serverless-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/follow-up-on-serverless-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received incredible feedback on my last week&amp;rsquo;s blog post Amazon API Gateway with Lambda is the Next Generation of Web Frameworks.
As Adrian Mace suggested, there is a new Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool from Amazon, called AWS CDK (Cloud Development Kit). I missed this awesome tool. To quote Adrian:
 &amp;ldquo;CDK allows you to define your infrastructure using imperative languages like TypeScript, Python, or Golang with the full powers that those languages can provide, and then ‘compiles down’ into Cloudformation templates upon deploy/synth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon API Gateway with Lambda is the Next Generation of Web Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/amazon-api-gateway-with-lambda-is-a-next-generation-of-web-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mitelman.engineering/blog/amazon-api-gateway-with-lambda-is-a-next-generation-of-web-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>A short history of web frameworks What is a web framework? A web framework is a set of tools for the rapid development of server-side applications that provides a boilerplate to simplify the implementation of common tasks. According to MDN, those tasks are routing URLs to appropriate handlers, interacting with databases, supporting sessions and user authorization, formatting output (e.g. HTML, JSON, XML), and improving security against web attacks. The most popular web frameworks are Ruby on Rails, Django, Flask, FastAPI, Express, Laravel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
